[AWAKEN]
[Episode 18]
Chen Kailai,
for your contribution
to eliminating Communist spies,
you are awarded a medal.
Seeing you get rewarded
makes me happier
than getting rewarded myself.
Why?
Because I'm your mentor.
I got credit because of your influence.
How can I face others in the future?
I have my pride.
You know what?
Favors are more fragile than your pride.
With this bronze medal,
you'll have
a bright future at No. 76.
I'm just a photographer.
Why do I need that?
People live for a bright future.
Otherwise,
it's just a waste of time.
Look.
Only the dead don't need it.
Come on in.
Leifeng Pagoda...
Leifeng Pagoda sacrificed himself.
It's not easy
for two people to come together.
There are some things
you should tell her sooner.
I'll tell her when she returns safely.
If I'd known it was the last time
we'd meet,
I would've asked him to stay for a meal.
He loved you.
He loved his ideals
and faith.
I'm ready.
I will die too.
You must stay alive.
For him,
and for yourself.
Newspapers!
I've found Du Huangqiao's place.
What are you going to do?
Kill him.
To avenge Zhao Qian?
He'll make a move on you sooner or later.
Now is not a good time to strike.
We can give the address
to the Hurricane Team.
Enough.
We came all the way
from the Northeast to Nanjing.
All this time,
it wasn't just to kill Du Huangqiao.
Son of a bitch!
The comrades around us
have left us one by one.
Fortunately,
you've always been here.
I won't allow you to leave before me.
I look so ugly in this photo.
Not just ugly.
This photo
might cost you your life.
You only have one way out now.
What?
Become my man.
Become one of us.
If you don't agree,
it'll be hard for me to save your life.
Tao Dachun could kill you at any moment
for being a traitor.
I'm not a traitor.
That's not up to you.
That's a label Du Huangqiao put on me!
Do you remember Shasha,
who helped you before?
That bastard Du Huangqiao.
He sent several men to gang-rape her,
driving her to her death.
Let go of me!
Get out! Don't touch me!
Cang Guanglian,
you liar.
You said you'd take care of me
for the rest of my life.
He did that?
I told you before
that staying with this kind of person
won't end well.
Unless...
you become mine.
That's the only way you'll stay alive.
Alright, I agree.
That's more like it.
What do you need me to do?
The Japanese have a project.
What is it?
It's called Project Slumber.
Is it the one related to Ishida?
Yes.
Ishida is dead.
I don't know any other Japanese.
Su Men and Du Huangqiao
both have connections with the Japanese.
You just need to stay by their side
and gather information.
Remember,
don't mess around.
Staying alive is the most important thing.
Hello.
Director Li,
I heard some bad news about you.
Tell me.
[Asamizawa,
Japanese Plum Blossom Agency Agent]
They found Yu Yingxiang's ledger.
Who did it?
That woman from Nanjing.
What is this?
The negatives of the photos
I took of you last time.
Also...
I promised Jinbao
to keep an eye on Project Slumber for her.
Maybe this way I can learn something
about the NBIS's movements.
That's a good thing.
The Hurricane Team
won't try to kill you anymore.
But you need to be more careful
in the future.
You'll be playing 3 roles at once.
I know.
But only one of them
is the real me.
No.
You must remember,
all three are you.
That's how you play them well.
Su Causeway is leaving.
Go say goodbye to her.
Sister.
Long time no see.
We will meet again.
Someone once said we would meet again,
but I never saw him again.
So this time,
I don't want to say that.
If I leave and never return,
then so be it.
The future is unknown.
I will remember you as you are now
and think of you as you were.
What we're doing now
is for the future.
Then we will definitely succeed.
Let me take a picture of you.
Why take a picture of me?
Your camera
should capture
the most beautiful things in the world.
What is "all the beauty in the world"?
The most beautiful thing
is peace.
I remember.
The most beautiful thing
is peace.
Sister!
Wait for me!
If you leave now,
what about the wedding?
That's not what I want.
I want to make my own choices.
Where are you going?
I don't know!
Will you come back?
Thank you!
Where can I find you?
We can't keep Su Men around anymore.
She is protected
by the Japanese and Nanjing.
Confronting her openly
might leave us vulnerable.
Then let's use someone else to do it.
The tickets are booked.
We're leaving for Nanjing
tomorrow morning.
Got it.
Come in.
How are the preparations?
Boss.
I've even thought of
the headline for tomorrow's tabloid.
It will be called "A Tragic Beauty:
Nanjing Inspector Shot Dead by Bandit."
Good.
Then tomorrow,
I'll have to buy a few more newspapers.
Sure thing, Boss.
Inspector Su.
General Kagesa,
may I have this dance?
Yes,
you may.
Du Huangqiao is acting weird today.
What's wrong?
I heard him say,
"Nanjing Inspector
Shot Dead by Bandit."
Be careful.
Captain Du.
The Green Gang has an operation
in the French Concession tonight.
They are coming for me.
Go home now
and move the stuff.
What about you?
Go quickly.
Follow Cui Enxi.
Yes.
-Director Li.
How is it going?
Everything is ready.
Inspector Su,
you're usually the first to leave.
You seem to be in high spirits today.
I can't always spoil the fun.
However,
the dance floor only shines
with you on it.
We've known each other for so long,
yet I...
have never danced with you.
It's because you have never invited me.
Please.
It's because you're too noble,
and a blind man like me
isn't worthy of you.
Then who gave you the courage this time?
Mr. Zhao.
It was Mr. Zhao who told me
that life is unpredictable,
all is vanity,
and one must enjoy life while they can.
Captain Du, you're a nostalgic person.
Aren't you, Inspector Su?
Nostalgia easily breaks one's heart.
Since Mr. Zhao is no longer with us,
I'll be bold enough...
to escort you home.
Don't bother.
I think it's better for you
to find a dancing girl.
Move!
Move! Get out of the way!
Ms. Su Men.
We suspect you
are involved
in a case we are investigating.
Please come with us.
Detective.
This is No. 76's turf.
What kind of huge case is it
that you need
to take our Inspector Su away?
Captain Du,
I am investigating under orders.
No comment.
Let's go.
I'll cooperate.
Move, move!
Continue!
What should we do?
She already knows about our operation.
We can't leave her alive.
Come on, charge over!
♪ This road is so very long ♪
I'm your bodyguard.
I'll protect you from now on.
♪ I don't seem to have done enough ♪
Go!
♪ I follow the warmth
of a heart held close ♪
Go!
♪ Moving on without looking back ♪
♪ I have so many things to tell you ♪
♪ But I don't think I can give you ♪
♪ The answer you want ♪
♪ Don't let yourself grieve too much ♪
♪ When you wake,
the sun will shine again ♪
♪ At the end of the road,
I'll be facing the way we came from ♪
♪ This love, to you and me ♪
♪ Is as light is to the night ♪
♪ And it brings me hope ♪
♪ There is nowhere left
for darkness to hide ♪
It'll be too late if we don't leave now!
♪ Dawn will find its way to your side ♪
♪ And it will never fade away ♪
Get in the car!
♪ Come, tell me what you have to say ♪
♪ And I know your answers ♪
♪ Won't change much for me ♪
♪ I have dreams of my own ♪
♪ Like the rising sun ♪
♪ They're in the distance
and in my heart ♪
♪ This love, to you and me ♪
♪ Is as light is to the night ♪
♪ It once gave me hope ♪
♪ There is nowhere left
for darkness to hide ♪
♪ Dawn will find its way to your side ♪
♪ This love, to you and me ♪
♪ Is as light is to the night ♪
♪ It gives me endless hope ♪
♪ There is nowhere left
for darkness to hide ♪
♪ Dawn will find its way to your side ♪
♪ It won't fade away ♪
♪ It will always be by your side ♪
Boss.
Cui Enxi is dead.
The ledger was not on her.
Why don't you die?
I will die for you.
With a face like yours,
no wonder your wife
is still willing to be with you.
Captain Du.
Everything in the safe has been taken out.
No ledger was found.
At least it wasn't a wasted trip.
Here.
Give it to the boys.
Thank you, Captain.
We didn't find the ledger.
How do we explain this to Director Li?
If I counted on you,
I would have died many times over.
The ledger is gone.
But Su Men is still alive.
I want to shut her up forever.
The temporary detention
is only for 2 days.
As long as we get the evidence
of Su Men colluding with the Communists,
even Hua Liang
won't be able to protect her.
You are Korean?
If you have nowhere to go,
stay with me from now on.
You are pretty.
I'll protect you from now on.
Have a bowl of wontons.
You haven't eaten all day.
I want them...
to pay in blood.
Is there anything I can help with?
Here.
This thing.
Captain Du said
this is the evidence of Su Men
colluding with the Communists.
Isn't this a little too half-hearted?
You messed up her house like this.
You know Inspector Su's temper.
She may settle the score with you
after this.
What are you thinking?
Colluding with the Communists.
Su Men is
completely finished this time.
Why didn't you come yesterday?
There were a lot of good things yesterday.
Alright. Go ahead and take the pictures.
Raise your glasses!
And you guys.
Cheers!
Come on!
Director.
Chen Kailai, what brings you here?
I'm here to deliver some photos.
I have an idea.
You teach me photography,
and I'll teach you how to do pedicures.
What do you think?
Pedicures? Forget it.
Director Li.
You use your art to serve your work.
Well done.
Good job.
Sit here.
I'll be leaving now.
Sit.
Danni, come here.
Keep my bro company.
Okay.
Let's go dance.
I don't know how.
Come on.
I... I really don't know how.
I'll teach you.
No, thanks.
Then let's have a drink.
I can't drink.
I got some news from the Japanese.
That woman will be released tomorrow.
You are so drunk?
Be careful.
I heard something happened at Paramount.
I remember
the first time
I met Inspector Su on the train.
She saved me.
I didn't expect someone so influential
to get into trouble.
Why are you feeling sorry
for that traitor?
Don't tell me you like that demoness.
From Li Musheng's death until now,
it feels
like a lifetime.
My cousin,
Mr. Zhao,
Auntie—
they all came
and left.
I feel like I'm living
in a movie,
or...
a fading photograph.
I think you've lost your mind.
Save your sympathy.
Sooner or later,
I will die too.
Don't forget you are my man now.
You could get a mission at any time.
There's no time for you to be sentimental.
They're all gone.
Who am I supposed to contact?
Hello?
Is this Fulai Photo Studio?
May I speak to Mr. Chen?
Speaking.
Would it be convenient for you
to send over
the photos Ms. Su took at your place?
Who did you say?